[Music]
I am Dr Magan Merra I a consultant
minimal access surgeon and bariatric
surgeon in muradabad City Apex hospital
muradabad is a tier 23 City uh near
Delhi and uh we have 100 bed multip
Speciality Hospital I've been practicing
here as a minimal access surgeon for the
last 15 years and I've recently started
working on the uh SSI Mantra robotic
system so my experience has been that uh
the interface that this robot provides
is good it is easy to learn and easy to
use obviously there are some challenges
when we learn anything new so the
biggest challenge for me is to forget
what I I do in laproscopy and to start
learning again what I need to do in
robotics uh but definitely it gives a
lot of
uh plus to me as a surgeon because it
makes me more comfortable during the
surgery so robotics gives me the ease to
do more complex surgeries in a better
way without getting
tired with SSI Mantra we also have this
advantage AG of a very reasonable cost
of the system as well as the uh the
consumables that come with it the
support provided by SSI Mantra is great
we have we have had uh two people two
Engineers with us throughout to help us
in any challenges that we need uh we
need them for and uh we have done
approximately 10 cases till now out of
these at least six have been complex
cases like uh laproscopic cardiomyotomy
with hius Hera repair we have done
various hernas in locations like upper
abdomen incisional hernas where we have
done a trans abdominal retromuscular
repair which is very difficult to do
even laparoscopically but with robot uh
we could do it in good time as well as
uh with a very per near perfect
result so I would recommend this to
every uh young surgeon who would like to
get into Robotics and at a reasonable
cost to himself and to his
patients with the reasonable expense
associated with the SSI Mantra system I
feel that it is going to bring a
revolution in the robotic healthc care
system the the way robotics is going to
get into the healthcare system and
definitely it is going to get
this uh robotic surgery to the doorsteps
of every individual who is living in
urban India and maybe in the near future
to rural India as well both the reasons
why because one because it is an Indian
system and uh we we have the wherewith
all to make the whole system and second
because of the reasonable cost
associated with the system I think it is
going to progress very fast in this
country
[Music]